Finding Aid for Computing Center (University of Michigan) records, 1952-1996
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Administrative Records 1959-1992
  - Reports
    - "Representative Sample of Facilities and Activities at the University of Michigan Bearing on Instructional Uses of Computing," 1971 (Box 15)
    - "Statistics Research Library," ca. 1973 (Box 15)
    - "Study of Programming Language Effectiveness," 1970 (Box 15)
    - "Technical 2 (Library Information Program) and 3 (Data Manipulation with Midas)," 1975-1976 (Box 15)
    - "Technical Specification for a Remotely Located Display Unit for the ARPA ConComp Project," 1966 (Box 15)
  - Research Systems
    - General 1989-1990, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Inventory 1990 (Box 15)
    - Managers Minutes 1991 (Box 15)
    - Planning Advisory Group 1990 (Box 15)
    - Report to Director 1990 (Box 15)
    - Retreat 1991 (Box 15)
  - Space Planning
    - 1984-1991, 3 folders (Box 15)
    - Information Technology Instructional Center (ITIC) (became Media Union) 1986-1988 (Box 15)
    - Open House, North Campus 1991 (Box 15)
- Computer Files
  The Computer Files series is comprised of 39 3.5" floppy disks that contain administrative documents, run data from MTS, and additional materials. The series also includes sample printouts.
  - (Includes administrative documents, "MTS Run Data," "CLS Data and UB," and "UB Summaries." Sample printouts included in folder), 39 floppy disks 3.5" (Box 16)
- MTS (Michigan Terminal System) 1968-1996
  The MTS (Michigan Terminal System) series (13.5 linear ft., 1968-1996) is comprised of three subseries: Distributions, Topical Files, and Workshops. The heart of the series is the distribution documentation (as the term documentation is used in the computing world) for the highly regarded operating system developed at the University of Michigan. The material is arranged chronologically by version, beginning with version 1.0 in 1968 and concluding with 6.0 in 1988. Each distribution typically includes computer printouts that carry instruction for technical installation and instruction for operating the system. For some versions, the record group includes master magnetic tapes. Material is housed by size and format, and documentation for a single version may be found in more than one box. Workshop files are an important complement to distribution data, documenting the cooperative nature of MTS, which was one of the first networked development efforts ever undertaken. Workshops were held annually for administrators and programmers from eight universities in three countries to share information about MTS development and to jointly analyze new features. The files include papers, presentations, agendas and schedules. Also of note is a 1990 MTS user study. Its goal was to define the system not only in terms of CPU, disk storage, etc., but by how the community was actually using the system. The series also includes programming staff memoranda, draft manuals, and a 1991 document on the future of MTS. The later details requirements for moving into distributed computing and requirements for the transfer and migration of current services to new ones.
  - Distribution Documentation (Paper) (Box 16)
  - (Note: Paper files are housed by size of computer printout; therefore, distribution documentation for a single version may be in more than one box.)
    - 1.0 1968 (see also box 25) (Box 16)
    - 1.1 1969 (Box 16)
    - 2.0 1969, 2 folders (Box 16)
    - 3.1 1973 (see also box 24) (Box 17)
    - 3.2 1974, 2 folders (Box 17)
      (see also box 24)
    - 4.0 1977, 3 folders (Box 18)
    - 4.1 1978, 3 folders (Box 18)
      (see also box 25)
    - 4.2 1979, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - 4.3 1980 (Box 19)
    - 4.5 (see box 25) (Box 19)
    - 5.0 1981-1984, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - 5.0 1981-1984, 3 folders (Box 20)
    - 5.1 1984, 3 folders (Box 20)
    - 5.1 A 1984 (Box 21)
    - 5.1 B 1984, 2 folders (Box 21)
    - 5.1 C 1985 (Box 21)
    - 5.1 D 1986 (Box 21)
    - 6.0 1988, 7 folders (Box 22)
    - 1.0 oversized printout (see also box 17) (Box 23)
    - 3.0, 3.1, and 3.2, 4.0 oversized printouts (see also box 18) (Box 23)
    - 4.1, 4.2, 4.5 (oversized printouts) (Box 24)
      (see also boxes 19 and 20)
  - Distribution Documentation (Magnetic tapes) (Box 25)
    - 2.1, 800 BPI; 2.5" magnetic tapes (data tapes (Box 25)
    - 5.0, 1600 BPI; 1.5" magnetic tape (data tape (Box 25)
    - 6.0, 6250 BPI; 6.5" magnetic tapes (data tapes (Box 25)
  - Topical (Box 26)
    (Oversize Computer Printouts)
    - Election Returns Program 1974 (Box 26)
    - System Documentation
      - July 1960 (Box 26)
      - November 1974 (Box 26)
  - Topical
    - Disk Disaster Recovery 1982 (Box 27)
    - Down Messages 1988 (Box 27)
    - Driver File Updates 1991 (Box 27)
    - External Users 1987-1988 (Box 27)
    - FLECS (Fortran Language with Extended Control Structures) System) 1974-1976 (Box 27)
    - Healthcare Knowledge Systems 1991-1992 (Box 27)
    - Help Database 1988-1990 (Box 27)
    - Hardware Purchase Justification 1990 (Box 27)
    - Issues 1990-1991 (Box 27)
    - Licensing 1988 (Box 27)
    - Meetings 1991 (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous 1969-1989, 3 folders (Box 27)
    - Operator's Manual 1982, 1988 (Box 27)
    - Organization and Features undated (Box 27)
    - Planning 1986-1990 (Box 27)
    - Programming Staff Memos 1966-1968 (Box 27)
    - Proposal, Future of MTS 1991 (Box 27)
    - Proprietary Software 1985 (Box 27)
    - Rates 1977, 1981, 1982, 1996 (Box 27)
    - Report: Cambridge 1971 (Box 27)
    - Report: University British Columbia 1974-1975 (Box 27)
    - Reports and Descriptions 1973-1977, undated (Box 27)
    - Spires Database undated (Box 27)
    - Supervisor Call Description (SVC) undated (Box 27)
    - System Statistics 1996 (Box 27)
    - Tutorial on Internal Organization for Time-Sharing 1969 (Box 27)
    - Use, Departmental 1990 (Box 27)
    - Usage Statistics 1985-1990 (Box 27)
    - Use Study by John Mackrell 1990, 4 folders (Box 27)
  - Workshops
    - Taped "Series of Lectures on the Michigan Terminal System," by Mike Alexander, Don Boettner, Jim Hamilton, Doug Smith undated (Box 28)
      (4 and 6.5 inch reels, 1 7/8 ips and lecture notes)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 28)
    - 1978, 4 folders (Box 28)
    - 1986-1987, 3 folders (Box 28)
    - 1988, 2 folders (Box 29)
    - 1988 Workshop Proceedings, "1st Intersystem Workshop, 14th MTS Workshop", 5 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 29)
    - 1989-1993, 5 folders (Box 29)
- Merit Network 1978-1989
  The Merit Network series (1 linear ft., 1978-1989) includes eight folders of board of director and director advisory committee correspondence, minutes and agendas for 1979 to 1989; NSF (National Science Foundation) proposals, correspondence and background for 1986-1988; and miscellaneous organizational files. Researchers will find more extensive material about Michigan's Merit network, its management and re-engineering of the NSFNET backbone service (a collaboration with IBM and MCI) and further description of the evolution of the Internet which it helped pioneer, in the Information Technology Division (ITD) record group.
  - Board of Directors and Director's Advisory Committee 1979-1989, 8 folders (Box 30)
  - Correspondence 1978-1983, 2 folders (Box 30)
  - National Science Foundation Proposal
    - Background 1987 (Box 30)
    - Correspondence 1987 (Box 30)
    - Proposals 1986-1988, 2 folders (Box 30)
  - Policies and Practices 1979-1985 (Box 30)
  - Reports 1986-1987 (Box 30)
  - Seminar 1988 (Box 30)
- MAD (Michigan Algorithm Decoder) 1960-1979
  The MAD (Michigan Algorithm Decoder) series (4 linear ft., 1960-1979) supplements, particularly with technical documentation, records from the earlier accession. The language, which provided a structure that fostered learning and teaching while also including the structure necessary for solving complex problems, was a key development in the evolution of computing at the university and broadly recognized as a major intellectual achievement. The records illustrate MAD's essential purpose -- to train large numbers of university students and to handle the large volume of university research problems in files of correspondence, developer and programmer notes, and reports and manuals. The series also includes three feet of MAD code printouts, some of which include penciled annotations.
  - Correspondence 1968-1979 (Box 31)
  - Developer's Notes
    - Externals 1967 (Box 31)
    - General 1967-1968 (Box 31)
    - Macros, Codes 1966-1968 (Box 31)
    - Minutes 1967-1968 (Box 31)
    - Storage and Allocation 1968 (Box 31)
  - Manuals
    - "A Computer Primer for the Mad Language," 1972 (Box 31)
    - "The Mad Language for the Philco," (Ford Motor Company), 1972 (Box 31)
    - "The Mad Language for the Philco," Revised (Ford Motor Company) 1972 (Box 31)
    - "The Mad Language for the Philco," Second Edition (Ford Motor Company) 1972 (Box 31)
    - "A Mad Primer," 1972 (Box 31)
    - "Michigan Algorithm Decoder," 1960 (Box 31)
    - "Michigan Algorithm Decoder," 1961 (Box 31)
    - "Michigan Algorithm Decoder," 1963 (Box 31)
    - "Michigan Algorithm Decoder," 1966 (Box 31)
    - "Michigan Algorithm Decoder," 1967 (Box 31)
  - Programmer's Notes, 3 folders (Box 31)
  - Oversized MAD Code Printouts (Box 32)
  - Oversized MAD Code Printouts (Box 33)
    (continued)
  - Oversized MAD Code Printouts (Box 34)
- Word Processing Project 1980-1982
  The Word Processing series (.5 linear ft., 1980-1982) adds further documentation to a Computing Center collaboration with IBM to develop text processing on computers. The three-year investigation was a $700,000 project, which was initiated with a conference to analyze the current state of the art in word processing techniques. It drew experts from across the United States. The records include background information, conference material, and advisory committee meeting minutes and notes.
  - Academic Authoring Requirements 1982 (Box 35)
  - Advisory Committee Minutes 1980-1981 (Box 35)
  - Authoring System Specification 1982 (Box 35)
  - Background 1980-1981 (Box 35)
  - Conference 1980 (Box 35)
  - Contract Correspondence 1980-1983, 2 folders (Box 35)
  - Guides and Reports 1980-1987 (Box 35)
  - Installation Planning 1981-1982 (Box 35)
  - Notes 1981 (Box 35)
  - Requirements and Strategies 1981 (Box 35)
  - Reviews 1980-1981 (Box 35)
  - Subcommittees 1981 (Box 35)
- Vendors 1974-1992
  The Vendors series (1.5 linear ft., 1974-1992), arranged alphabetically, and Software Contracts series (2 linear ft., 1966-1992), also alphabetically arranged, together document associations with computer companies and the typical types of legal arrangements made with software producers. While associations with several major computer companies are represented in the Vendors series, a majority of the files in this second accession of the record group are IBM related, most significantly for the IFS (Institutional File System) collaboration, which was originally dubbed internally, "Strawman." Begun in 1988, and directed by Gregory Marks, deputy vice provost for information technology, IFS created an innovative computing environment for file storage and retrieval for workstations on campus (anticipated in the 1990s to be more than 30,000 machines). IFS served as a model for other universities and businesses linking heterogeneous mainframes, minicomputers and workstations running different operating systems. The records contain background, the development plan, status reports, meeting minutes and notes. There is some additional documentation for IFS in the CITI (Center for Information Technology Integration) files of the Topical Files series of this record group and more complete documentation in the Information Technology Division (ITD) record group (including detailed planning documents). Software was managed by Software Services, which had responsibility for operating systems, workstation support, applications and servers, and scientific computation. The Software Contracts files are mainly comprised of formal contracts defining conditions of use for a broad range of software.
  - Amdahl 1986-1987 (Box 35)
  - Ameritech 1987 (Box 35)
  - Apple 1986-1988, 2 folders (Box 35)
  - Apple University Consortium 1986-1987 (Box 35)
  - Control Data Proposal, Volumes 1, 2, and 3 1964, 2 folders (Box 35)
  - Digital 1987-1988 (Box 35)
  - General Electric Time Sharing Proposal 1965 (Box 35)
  - General Electric 635 1964-1965 (Box 35)
  - IBM
    - 360
      - Proposal Documents 1964-1965 (Box 36)
      - Specifications and Implementation Problems, Procurement 1964-1967 (Box 36)
      - Service Agreement 1988 (Box 36)
    - 3090
      - Acquisition 1986 (Box 36)
      - Financial 1986 (Box 36)
      - General 1986-1987 (Box 36)
    - Briefings 1987 (Box 36)
    - General 1986 (Box 36)
    - IFS (Institutional File System)
      - General 1990-1991 (Box 36)
      - Background 1990 (Box 36)
      - Development Plan 1990 (Box 36)
      - Macintosh User Guide 1990 (Box 36)
      - Status Reports 1990-1991 (Box 36)
      - Straw Man Meeting June 30, 1987 (Box 36)
      - Straw Man Files 1987-1988 (Box 36)
    - Joint Projects 1986-1987 (Box 36)
    - Networking undated (Box 36)
    - NEXT 1987-1989, 2 folders (Box 36)
    - Notes and Correspondence 1987-1989 (Box 36)
    - Steering Committee 1987-1988 (Box 36)
    - Sun 1987 (Box 36)
    - Miscellaneous 1987-1989 (Box 36)
- Software Contracts
  The Software Contracts files are mainly comprised of formal contracts defining conditions of use for a broad range of software.
  - General, Michigan Terminal System (MTS) Software 1988-1989 (Box 37)
  - AFS 1992 (Box 37)
  - Andor Systems 1990 (Box 37)
  - APL-PLUS PC 1983-1984 (Box 37)
  - Apollo 1987 (Box 37)
  - AT&T Unix 1983-1987 (Box 37)
  - AT&T C/370 Language Compiler 1977-1988 (Box 37)
  - Bell Laboratories 1980 (Box 37)
  - Berkeley 1987 (Box 37)
  - BMDP Statistical Software 1985-1992 (Box 37)
  - BTI Maintenance 1991 (Box 37)
  - CART Software 1984-1985 (Box 37)
  - Code Generator Generator (COGG) Software 1982-1983 (Box 37)
  - Compu View undated (Box 37)
  - Course Writer 1969-1975 (Box 37)
  - Data South 1991 (Box 37)
  - DataText 1987-1992 (Box 37)
  - Digital Equipment Corporation 1989-1991 (Box 37)
  - EPS/FCS undated (Box 37)
  - EQS Structural Equations Program 1985-1991 (Box 37)
  - EXECUCOM 1985-1986 (Box 37)
  - GPSS Wolverine Software 1980-1985 (Box 37)
  - GQOPT 1983 (Box 37)
  - IBM 1981-1992, 2 folders (Box 37)
  - IBM Fortran 1985-1987 (Box 37)
  - IBM IFS 1991 (Box 37)
  - Interactive Financial Planning System (IFPS) undated (Box 37)
  - Library 1987 (Box 37)
  - Maclib Micros undated (Box 37)
  - MAGI 1981 (Box 37)
  - MATLIB 1982 (Box 37)
  - MCP Programs 1982-1983 (Box 37)
  - Minitab 1986 (Box 37)
  - MSC / NASTRAN 1991 (Box 37)
  - MTS 1980-1987 (Box 37)
  - MUMPS 1985 (Box 37)
  - Numerical Algorithm Group 1985-1986 (Box 37)
  - NCAR Graphics 1984-1985 (Box 37)
  - Oxford Concordance Program 1981-1982 (Box 37)
  - NLP 1986 (Box 37)
  - Ontel 1978-1983 (Box 37)
  - Pascal 1976-1984 (Box 37)
  - Patient Management Category (PMC) 1991 (Box 37)
  - P Fort 1977-1979 (Box 37)
  - PL / C 1970-1985 (Box 37)
  - PLOT 1985-1986 (Box 37)
  - PMC 1988 (Box 37)
  - Precision Visuals 1982-1990 (Box 37)
  - Programs From Other Installations 1966-1975 (Box 38)
  - Rejected 1976-1979 (Box 38)
  - S-Software 1985-1986 (Box 38)
  - SAS 1984-1988, 3 folders (Box 38)
  - Scientific Computing Associates 1985, 1991 (Box 38)
  - Shazam 1987 (Box 38)
  - SHRINK undated (Box 38)
  - Simscript 1979-1985 (Box 38)
  - SIMU-SOLV 1987-1988 (Box 38)
  - Spires 1985 (Box 38)
  - Spitball and Snowball 1978 (Box 38)
  - SPSSX 1992 (Box 38)
  - Structural Dynamics Research Corp 1981 (Box 38)
  - SysteMetrics 1987 (Box 38)
  - Tektronix 1984 (Box 38)
  - Tel l-A-Graf 1982-1984 (Box 38)
  - TextSet 1984-1985 (Box 38)
  - Troll 1978-1988 (Box 38)
  - TSP 1985-1990 (Box 38)
  - UBC TRANS 1980 (Box 38)
  - UNSP 1979-1981 (Box 38)
  - Unsupported Software Writeups 1977 (Box 38)
  - WATBOL 1974-1983 (Box 38)
  - Waterloo Basic, Prolog 1981-1983 (Box 38)
  - Xerox 1983-1984 (Box 38)
  - Miscellaneous 1981-1991, 2 folders (Box 38)
- Topical Files 1983-1992
  The Topical Files series (4 linear ft., 1983-1992), arranged alphabetically, include records that reflect the Computing Center's relationships with other university units, the development of conferencing and an e-mail system, a movement into computer sales, the development of policy, and outreach to users. The most extensive documentation is for CITI (Center for Information Technology Integration), ITD's research / development unit that worked to develop joint projects with industrial partners and liaisons with key equipment suppliers. There are also several files from User Services, the ITD unit charged with education, documentation, user relations, consulting and local area networking. Files include a 1990 workshop, user surveys for 1986 and 1988, and a 1992 graduate school user survey.
  - Apple Truckload Sale 1987-1988 (Box 39)
  - Apple University Consortium (AUC) 1988, 2 folders (Box 39)
  - BITNET 1986-1987 (Box 39)
  - Business School 1986-1991 (Box 39)
  - Campus Information Center 1987 (Box 39)
  - Campus Sites 1989 (Box 39)
  - Center for Information Technology Integration (CITI) 1986-1989
    - General 1986-1989, 5 folders (Box 39)
    - Apollo 1986-1988 (Box 39)
    - Apple 1986-1987 (Box 39)
    - Budget 1986-1987 (Box 39)
    - EXPRES (Experimental Research in Electronic Submission) 1986-1988, 2 folders (Box 39)
  - Center for Statistical Consultation and Research 1991 (Box 39)
  - Chemistry 1986-1988, 2 folders (Box 39)
  - CICnet (Committee for Institutional Cooperation) 1986 (Box 39)
  - Coalition Academic Supercomputing Center 1991 (Box 39)
  - Commission on Professional and Hospital Activities 1990 (Box 39)
  - Computer Abuse 1988 (Box 39)
  - Computer Kick-Off and Sales 1987-1989, 2 folders (Box 39)
  - Conditions of Use 1987-1988 (Box 39)
  - Conferencing and Conditions of Use 1987-1988 (Box 39)
  - Conferencing Abuse Issues 1987-1988 (Box 39)
  - Construction Projects 1986 (Box 39)
  - Consulting at University of Michigan 1986 (Box 39)
  - Copyright Issues 1988-1991 (Box 39)
  - Computing Resources 1986-1987 (Box 39)
  - Corporation for Open Systems 1986 (Box 39)
  - Course of Action 1987 (Box 39)
  - Database, University 1980-1983 (Box 39)
  - Dearborn 1990 (Box 39)
  - Dentistry 1987 (Box 39)
  - Desktop Publishing 1985 (Box 39)
  - Disaster Recovery,1982 (Box 39)
  - Documentation Inventory Control System 1980 (Box 40)
  - E-Mail System and Phone Book 1986-1991 (Box 40)
  - Education Center (Microcomputer) 1987 (Box 40)
  - Educational Uses of Computing 1987 (Box 40)
  - Education, School of 1987 (Box 40)
  - Electronic Data Systems (EDS) 1986-1987 (Box 40)
  - Ethics 1987-1988 (Box 40)
  - Engineering, College of 1983-1987 (Box 40)
  - External Networks 1986 (Box 40)
  - Fleming, Robben, IT Briefing 1987 (Box 40)
  - Flint 1989 (Box 40)
  - Forum on Information Technology 1987 (Box 40)
  - Form Text Formatting 1986 (Box 40)
  - Freedom of Information Act 1987 (Box 40)
  - Hardware and Software (Box 40)
  - Healthcare Knowledge Resources 1992 (Box 40)
  - Health Services 1987 (Box 40)
  - Hypercard 1987 (Box 40)
  - Improper Use 1985-1987 (Box 40)
  - InfoDisk 1987 (Box 40)
  - InfoNet 1989 (Box 40)
  - InfoX 1990-1991 (Box 40)
  - Intersystem Project 1987 (Box 40)
  - ICPSR 1987-1988 (Box 40)
  - Laboratory of Scientific Computation 1986-1987 (Box 40)
  - Large-Scale Computing 1986-1988 (Box 40)
  - Legal Issues 1989 (Box 40)
  - Library Science School 1986-1987 (Box 40)
  - Libraries, University 1985-1990, 3 folders (Box 40)
  - Literature, Science and the Arts Workstation Laboratory 1986-1988 (Box 40)
  - LS&A, General 1984-1991 (Box 40)
  - Local Area Network 1987-1989 (Box 40)
  - Local Dealers 1986-1988 (Box 40)
  - Macintosh System 7.0 1991 (Box 40)
  - Mail Service 1987 (Box 41)
  - Maintenance 1987 (Box 41)
  - Medical Center 1986-1988 (Box 41)
  - Michigan Inter-University Committee on Information Systems 1984-1987 (Box 41)
  - Michigan Media 1987-1988 (Box 41)
  - Microcomputing Group 1986 (Box 41)
  - Micro-Maintenance 1986-1989 (Box 41)
  - Micro-Sales Program 1986-1989 (Box 41)
  - Micro Software 1987 (Box 41)
  - Mirlyn 1989 (Box 41)
  - Music / Dance 1986-1987 (Box 41)
  - Networking
    - General 1985-1987 (Box 41)
    - Core Network Witac,1988 (Box 41)
    - Proposal 1980 (Box 41)
    - PTE, Banyon 1987-1988 (Box 41)
  - Northern Telecom 1987-1988 (Box 41)
  - Office Automation undated (Box 41)
  - Office of Instructional Technology 1987-1988 (Box 41)
  - Ombudsman 1987 (Box 41)
  - On Call Service 1989 (Box 41)
  - Operations 1986-1989 (Box 41)
  - Oracle 1991 (Box 41)
  - PEX Sample Server 1988 (Box 41)
  - PC Tie Program 1986-1987 (Box 41)
  - Phototypesetter, 1988 (Box 41)
  - Physics 1986 (Box 41)
  - Population Studies Center 1988 (Box 41)
  - Production Statistics 1988 (Box 41)
  - Professional Bibliographics System 1987-1988 (Box 41)
  - Programs (and who is responsible) undated (Box 41)
  - ProNet 1986 (Box 41)
  - Public Facilities 1986-1989 (Box 41)
  - Public Facilities, Art and Architecture 1987 (Box 41)
  - Publication Lists and Biography (Box 41)
  - Publicity 1986-1987 (Box 41)
  - Recycle Proposal 1987 (Box 41)
  - Renaissance Liturgical Imprints 1986 (Box 41)
  - Residence Halls Computing Program 1987-1988 (Box 41)
  - Security 1986-1991 (Box 41)
  - Software, Licensing, and Use 1987-1991 (Box 41)
  - Software Policy 1987 (Box 42)
  - Software Selection 1988 (Box 42)
  - Software Services 1989-1990 (Box 42)
  - Spell Check undated (Box 42)
  - Statistical Laboratory 1982-1988 (Box 42)
  - Student Organizations 1987 (Box 42)
  - Statistical Support 1987-1988 (Box 42)
  - Student Organizations Project 1987 (Box 42)
  - Suggestions 1986 (Box 42)
  - Supercomputers 1988 (Box 42)
  - Support for Hardware and Software 1987 (Box 42)
  - Tapes, Magnetic 1987 (Box 42)
  - TCP Protocols 1987 (Box 42)
  - Telecommunications 1986-1988 (Box 42)
  - Total Quality Management 1990-1991 (Box 42)
  - Translate Day 1988 (Box 42)
  - Truckload Sale, Computer Weekend 1986 (Box 42)
  - University Information Systems 1990 (Box 42)
  - University of Michigan Posting System 1990 (Box 42)
  - UNIX 1986-1991, 3 folders (Box 42)
  - User Services
    - General 1986-1987 (Box 42)
    - User Services Workshop 1990 (Box 42)
    - User Survey 1986, 1988 (Box 42)
    - User Survey, Graduate School 1992 (Box 42)
  - Viris 1988-1989 (Box 42)
  - Visualization Lab 1989 (Box 42)
  - Women In Computing 1983-1991 (Box 42)
  - X-Windows 1986-1987 (Box 42)
- Historical Files 1967-2011
  The Historical Files series contains materials (a video and PDF file of scanned images) from the Computing Center's 45th anniversary celebration and reception for original director Robert C. F. Bartels in 2004; instructional videos on punch card machine and MTS operation; papers on the Center's history and the development of time sharing systems; and a bibliography and snapshot of the MTS Wikipedia page from 2011.
  - 45th anniversary and reception honoring Robert C. F. Bartels
    - Posters, memory book, and collected materials 2004
    - Video 2004
  - Bibliography 2011
  - Movies
    - Advanced Use of the IBM 29 Card Punch 1968
    - Basic Operation of the IBM 29 Card Punch 1967
    - Basic Operation of MTS 1969
  - Papers
    - "Computing at Michigan: From the MTS and Computing Center to ITD and Microcomputers" by Thomas Madden 1999
    - "Time Sharing Supervisor Programs" by Michael T. Alexander 1971
  - Snapshot of MTS Wikipedia page 2011
- MTS (Michigan Terminal System)